"In the decade of the 1930s,
even the great city of Metropolis...
... was not spared the ravages
of the worldwide depression.
In the times of fear and confusion,
the job of informing the public...
... was the responsibility
of the Daily Planet...
... a great metropolitan newspaper,
whose reputation for clarity and truth...
... had become a symbol of hope
for the city of Metropolis. "
This is no fantasy...
...no careless product
of wild imagination.
No, my good friends...
These indictments
I have brought you today...
...the specific charges listed herein
against the individuals...
...their acts of treason,
their ultimate aim of sedition...
...these are matters of undeniable fact.
I ask you now to pronounce judgment...
...on those accused.
On this...
This mindless aberration,
whose only means of expression...
...are wanton violence and destruction.
On the woman, Ursa...
...whose perversions
and unreasoning hatred of all mankind...
...have threatened even the children
of the planet Krypton.
Finally, General Zod.
Once trusted by this council...
...charged with maintaining the defense
of the planet Krypton itself.
Chief architect
of this intended revolution...
...and author of this insidious plot
to establish a new order amongst us...
...with himself as absolute ruler.
You have heard the evidence.
The decision of the council
will now be heard.
Guilty.
The vote must be unanimous, Jor-El.
It has therefore
now become your decision.
You alone will condemn us if you wish...
...and you alone
will be held responsible by me.
Join us.
You have been known to disagree
with the council before.
Yours could become an important voice
in the new order...
...second only to my own.
I offer you a chance for greatness, Jor-El!
Take it! Join us!
You will bow down before me, Jor-El.
I swear it.
No matter that it takes an eternity,
you will bow down before me!
Both you...
...and then one day...
...your heirs!
No!
- Let us out of here!
- Help me!
- Forgive me!
- I shall return!
Forgive me!
I shall return!
An unpleasant duty
has been masterly performed, Jor-El.
They have received the fate
they deserved.
Isolation in the Phantom Zone...
...an eternal living death.
A chance for life, nonetheless.
As opposed to us.
It's suicide. No, it's worse.
It's genocide.
Be warned, Jor-El.
The council has already evaluated
this outlandish theory of yours.
My friends, you know me to be
neither rash nor impulsive.
I am not given to wild,
unsupported statements.
And I tell you that we must
evacuate this planet immediately.
Jor-El, you are one
of Krypton's greatest scientists.
Yes, but so is Vond-Ah.
It isn't that they question your data.
The facts are undeniable.
It's your conclusions
we find unsupportable.
This planet will explode
within 30 days, if not sooner.
I tell you, Krypton
is simply shifting its orbit.
Jor-El, be reasonable.
My friend...
...I have never been otherwise.
This madness is yours.
This discussion is terminated.
The decision of the council is final.
Any attempt by you to create a climate
of fear and panic among the populace...
...must be deemed by us
an act of insurrection.
You would accuse me of insurrection?
Has it now become a crime
to cherish life?
You would be banished
to endless imprisonment...
...in the Phantom Zone...
...the eternal void...
...which you yourself discovered.
Will you abide by the council's decision?
I will remain silent.
Neither I, nor my wife
will leave Krypton.
Have you finished?
Nearly.
It's the only answer, Lara.
If he remains here with us
he will die as surely as we will.
But why Earth, Jor-El?
They're primitives
thousands of years behind us.
He will need that advantage to survive.
Their atmosphere will sustain him.
He will defy their gravity.
He will look like one of them.
He won't be one of them.
No.
His dense molecular structure
will make him strong.
He'll be odd. Different.
He'll be fast. Virtually invulnerable.
Isolated, alone.
He will not be alone.
He will never be alone.
The energy input to Jor-El's quarters
is now in excess.
Our data indicates the loss
is due to a misuse of energy.
Investigate.
And if the investigation
proves correct?
He knew the penalty he faced.
He even is a member of this council.
The law will be upheld.
You will travel far, my little Kal-El.
But we will never leave you...
...even in the face of our deaths.
The richness of our lives,
it will be yours.
All that I have, all that I've learned,
everything I feel...
...all this and more...
...I bequeath you, my son.
You will carry me inside you
all the days of your life.
You will make my strength your own,
see my life through your eyes...
...as your life will be seen through mine.
The son becomes the father,
and the father the son.
This is all I...
All I can send you...
...Kal-El.
Stop. Stop, stop!
- which Einstein
called his theory of relativity.
Embedded in the crystals before you
is the total accumulation of all literature...
... and scientific fact
from dozens of other worlds...
... spanning the 28 known galaxies.
Early Chinese writings
point out the complex relationships...
By carrying this complex equation
to its ultimate power, my son...
Chief among these powers
will be your sight...
... your strength, your hearing...
... your ability to propel yourself
at almost limitless speed.
The early history of our universe
was a bloody mosaic of interplanetary war.
Each of the six galaxies
which you will pass through...
... contain their own individual law,
space and time.
It is forbidden for you
to interfere with human history.
What was that?
Now, wouldn't that beat all get-out?
Will you... You...
Pa...
Oh, my.
All these years,
as happy as we've been...
...how I've prayed the good Lord...
...see fit to give us a child.
Honey, will you hand me
that rag up there.
You take things easy, Jonathan.
Remember what Doc Frye said
about that heart of yours.
Now the first thing we've got
to do when we get home is find out...
...who that boy's proper family is.
He hasn't got any.
Not around here, anyway.
Martha, are you thinking
what I think you're thinking?
We could say he's the child
of my cousin in North Dakota.
And just now orphaned.
- Oh, Martha.
- Jonathan, he's only a baby.
Martha...
Now, you saw how we found him.
Martha Clark Kent, are you
listening to what I'm saying?
Jonathan!
Come on, gang.
Come on.
- That was a great game, huh?
- Yeah, but next week we're...
All right.
Come on, gang, hustle. Let's go.
Stack your helmets neatly.
Remember about those uniforms.
Cleaned and washed by tomorrow...
...and looking like a football team.
Clark, have the clothes
washed and ready...
...for tomorrow's game.
- Yes, sir.
Got to beat Mount Vernon High!
- Can you give me a lift?
- Home early!
Lana? Don't bother with these, huh?
I'll take them in with
the other equipment.
- Thank you, Clark.
- Sure.
Listen, a whole bunch of us
are going up to Mary Ellen's...
...play some records...
Would you like to come?
Sure. Sounds like it'd be a lot of fun.
Kent can't make it.
Still got a lot of work to do.
What are you talking about?
I just finished stacking all the...
All that?
Oh, Brad.
- Hey, come on, Lana.
- Come on, Lana.
Come on, let's go.
- He's got to clean up.
- Bye, Clark.
- Yeah. Bye, Lana.
- Clean this up, Clark.
- Let's go.
- Bye, Clark.
- We're off to Mary Ellen's.
- See you, Clark.
All right.
- Bye, Clark.
Bye, Clark. See you tomorrow. Bye-bye.
Golly, I saw a boy out there
run as fast as the train!
Faster even!
Lois Lane, you have
a writer's gift for invention.
- I'll say that for you.
- But... But...
Lois, please read your book.
No one ever believes me.
Hey, look. There's Clark.
How come he's here?
Clark.
How'd you get here so fast?
- I ran.
- Ran, huh?
Told you he's an oddball.
Let's get out of here.
Been showing off a bit,
haven't you, son?
I didn't mean to show off, Pa.
It's just that, guys like that Brad,
I just want to tear them apart.
Yeah. I know.
- Yeah, I know I shouldn't.
- Yeah, I know...
...you can do all these amazing things...
...and sometimes you think
that you will just go bust...
...unless you can tell people about it.
Yeah. I mean, every time
I get the football...
...I can make a touchdown. Every time.
- That's for sure.
I mean, is it showing off
if somebody's doing...
...the things he's capable of doing?
Is a bird showing off when it flies?
No. No, now you listen to me.
When you first came to us,
we thought people...
...would come take you away
because when they found out...
...you know, the things you could do,
and that worried us a lot.
Then a man gets older,
and he thinks very differently...
...and things get very clear.
And there's one thing I do know, son...
...and that is you are here for a reason.
I don't know whose reason,
but whatever the reason...
...maybe it's because...
I don't know, it's...
But I do know one thing:
It's not to score touchdowns.
Thanks, Dad.
I'll race you to it. Dad.
- You will, huh?
- Come on. Come on, Pop, run.
Come on. Move. Move.
Yeah, go, go, go. Come on, run.
Hey, Baron! Hey, Baron. Hey, boy.
Oh, no.
Jonathan.
Jonathan!
Dad.
No!
Jonathan!
All those things I can do...
All those powers...
And I couldn't even save him.
Clark, get up.
Good morning, Smiley.
Clark, breakfast.
Are you gonna sleep all day?
Clark, come on. Get up.
I have to leave.
I knew this time would come.
We both knew it...
...from the day we found you.
I talked to Ben Hubbard yesterday...
...and he said that he'd be happy
to help out from now on.
Mother...
I know, son.
I know.
Do you know where you're headed?
North.
Remember us, son.
Always remember us.
My son...
... you do not remember me.
I am Jor-El.
I'm your father.
By now, you will have reached
your 18th year...
... as it is measured on Earth.
By that reckoning,
I will have been dead...
... for many thousands of your years.
The knowledge...
... that I have,
matters physical and historic...
... I've given you fully on your voyage
to your new home.
These are important matters, to be sure,
but still matters of mere fact.
There are questions to be asked.
And it is time for you to do so.
Here in this...
This Fortress of Solitude...
... we shall try to find
the answers together.
So, my son...
... speak.
Who am I?
Your name is Kal-El.
You are the only survivor
of the planet Krypton.
Even though you've been
raised as a human being...
... you are not one of them.
You have great powers...
... only some of which
you have as yet discovered.
Come with me now, my son...
... as we break through the bonds
of your earthly confinement.
Traveling through time and space
in the six known dimensions.
Your powers will far exceed
those of mortal men.
It is forbidden for you to interfere
with human history.
Rather, let your leadership
stir others to.
In this next year, we shall
examine the human heart.
It is more fragile than your own.
For the past two years...
As we pass through the flaming turmoil
which is the edge of your own galaxy...
... we'll enter the realm
of the red Krypton sun...
... source of your strength
and nourishment...
... cause of our eventual destruction.
The planet Krypton, my son.
Your home, as it was.
This year, we shall examine
the various concepts of immortality...
... and their basis in actual fact.
The total accumulation of all knowledge,
spanning the 28 known galaxies...
... is embedded in the crystals
which I have sent along with you.
Study them well, my son...
... and learn from them.
We've reasoned out logical judgments.
By the time you return
to the confines of your galaxy...
... twelve of your years will have passed.
For this reason, among others,
I have chosen Earth for you.
It is now time for you
to rejoin your new world...
... and to serve its collective humanity.
Live as one of them, Kal-El...
... to discover where your strength
and your power are needed.
Always hold in your heart
the pride of your special heritage.
They can be a great people, Kal-El.
They wish to be.
They only lack the light to show the way.
For this reason above all,
their capacity for good...
... I have sent them you...
... my only son.
Okay, this is it, mac, the Daily Planet.
Fresh fruit. Hey, lady,
how about a tomato?
Fresh fruit.
Hey, baby, how's it going?
Hey, fresh fruit and vegetables.
They're so fresh...
Fresh fruit and vegetables.
Get them while they're hot.
Look at these tomatoes.
Aren't they beautiful?
He did a great job.
You see his article this morning?
Smile.
- How many T's in "bloodletting"?
- Two.
- What are you writing, Miss Lane?
- An ode to spring.
How do you spell "massacre"?
- M-A-S-S-A-C-R-E.
- A... C...
...R- E. Thank you.
Golly, how come you get
all the great stories?
A good reporter doesn't
get great stories, Jimmy.
A good reporter makes them great.
Here's that story on the East Side murder.
I see it as a banner headline,
front page, maybe my picture...
There's only one P in "rapist."
Lois Lane, say hello to Clark Kent.
- Told you one P.
- Hello, Miss Lane. How are...?
Remember my exposé
on the sex and drug orgies...
...in the senior citizens home?
How you doing?
Jimmy Olsen, photographer.
- Oh, hi. Clark Kent. Nice to meet you.
- Yeah.
It's got everything. It's got sex,
violence, the ethnic angle...
So does a lady wrestler
with a foreign accent.
- Kent, can you open this?
- Oh, sure, Mr. White.
This could be a series of articles:
"Making Sense of Senseless Killings,"
by Lois Lane.
We get psychologists, sociologists...
Lois, you're pushing a bunch
of rinky-dink tabloid garbage.
- The Daily Planet has a tradition...
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Gosh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to shake it up like that.
Oh, of course not, Lois.
Why would anyone want to make
a total stranger look like a fool?
- I'll take that.
- Oh, thank... I'm sorry, Mr. White.
Olsen, why am I paying you when I should
have you arrested for loitering?
- Go get Mr... A towel.
- Kent.
- Move, kid, move.
- Right, chief.
- Make mine black, no sugar.
- And don't call me sugar.
- "Blood is in Metropolis...
- Right, sugar.
...while the crocuses bloom."
Chief wants coffee, no sugar.
I'll take tea with lemon.
Lois, why don't you take Kent
out to meet everybody, huh?
Just introduce him around.
He's starting with the paper today.
I'm giving him the city beat.
Chief, that's my beat.
Lois, Clark Kent may seem like just
a mild-mannered reporter, but listen...
...not only does he know how to treat
his editor in chief with respect...
...not only does he have a snappy,
punchy prose style...
...but he is, in my 40 years in this business,
the fastest typist I've ever seen.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Here, you forgot my article.
Oh, excuse me, Mr. White?
I was wondering if perhaps
you could arrange for half my salary...
...to be sent to this address
on a weekly basis.
- Your bookie, right?
- My what?
Don't tell me, he sends a check every week
to his sweet, gray-haired old mother.
Actually, she's silver-haired.
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you very much, Mr. White.
Excuse me.
Well...
Any more at home like you?
Not really, no.
I didn't think so.
- Well, get yourself a desk over here.
- Over here?
Yeah, right here.
There are some papers in a pile...
Sorry. Excuse me.
- Hi, Bill Breesen.
- Hi, Clark Kent.
- Nice to meet you.
- Welcome aboard.
- Here's your towel, Mr. Clark.
- Kent.
- What?
- Clark Kent.
- Jimmy Olsen.
- Yeah. It's fantastic.
- So you...?
- I met this really great guy.
- Hey, fabulous.
Yeah, fabulous.
I met him at this dude ranch.
- Did...? I used to ride.
- Yeah, I haven't been since I was 7.
- Oh, I gotta mail these letters.
- Okay, bye. Good luck tonight.
- Oh, hi, Clark.
- Hi, Lois.
How did you like your first day?
Well, frankly, the hours
were sort of longer than I expected...
...but on the whole, I mean, meeting you
and Jimmy Olsen and Mr. White...
...gosh, I'd say it's been swell.
- Swell?
- Yeah.
You know, Clark, there are very few people
left in the world...
...who feel comfortable
saying that word.
- What word?
- "Swell."
Really? I always thought
it was kind of natural.
- I'm sorry.
- Clark.
It's all right.
- Sorry, Lois.
- Oh, hi, Rex.
- Oh, Lois.
- See anything good today?
- Not until you came along.
- Lois?
- Oh, Rex, this is...
- Clark Kent.
- Yeah, hi, see you around.
- Bye.
- Lois?
- Hey, where you going?
- Can I help you with your coat?
- Oh, yeah. Thanks.
- So you like Mr. White.
- I thought he was a nice guy.
- Jimmy Olsen was fantastic.
- Hey, come here.
Come on, come on. Get in here.
Hurry up. Come on.
- We'd better get out of here.
- I think we'd better do what he says.
- Come on, come on. Get in here, quick.
- Don't do anything.
- That's it.
- We're coming.
- Come on.
- We're coming. Excuse me.
- Go on, back there.
- Here?
Please don't point that at me, sir.
- You could hurt somebody with that.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Okay, okay, hold it there.
- Just a minute, mister.
I realize of course that times
are tough for some these days...
...but this isn't the answer.
You can't solve society's problems
with a gun.
You know something, buddy? You're right.
I'm gonna turn over a new leaf.
Good for you, sir. That's the spirit.
He doesn't really want to hurt anybody.
- Right after I rip off this lady's purse.
- Of course.
Now come on, lady, hand it over.
Lois, I think maybe you better...
Lois, what are you doing?
Clark! Clark.
Clark, are you all right? Clark!
What happened?
Golly. I guess I must have fainted.
Fainted?
- You fainted?
- Sorry.
Swell.
Really, Lois, supposing that man
had shot you?
Is it worth risking your life over $ 10,
two credit cards, a hairbrush, and lipstick?
- How did you know that?
- Know what?
You just described the exact contents
of my purse.
Wild guess.
Taxi!
- Hey.
- Hi, Otis.
- So, what's happening, partner?
- Look what we got.
- Let's take him.
- Wait a minute.
Maybe he'll lead us
to the big man himself.
- Lex Luthor?
- You got it, Armus.
We'll make captain by midnight.
Hey, what do you read?
XK-101 rocket to be used.
- Hey, Matt.
- Hey, hey, Otis.
Just getting the Daily Planet here.
Hey, what do you read?
Down, down.
Okay, okay.
Okay. All right. See, I'm paying him.
I got a pretzel too.
Thanks, Otis. Okay.
How many did he take, Shutzy?
This is Metropolis 46. We're on foot.
Over and out.
Let's go.
Your attention, please.
The Metropolis Flyer is now
ready for departure...
... on the upper level, track six,
stopping at New Rochelle.
All right, he's going down
to the train platform. I'm going after him.
Okay, Harry. I'll call for backup.
Be careful, now.
- All right, Armus, all right.
- All aboard, please.
Now boarding on the lower level...
Ten minutes, folks.
Come on, air-conditioned cars.
Mount Vernon, Poughkeepsie, Glen Corners.
Aboard now. All aboard.
Metropolis Transportation.
Buffalo, Syracuse.
Smoking cars are forward.
Move along, now.
Put your luggage up the top.
Smoking cars forward.
All aboard. Boarding.
Armus, Armus, make it track 22.
I seen him, and I'm right on him.
Lower level, track 22.
So that's it.
It's amazing that brain can generate
enough power to keep those legs moving.
Harry.
Harry, where are you? Harry.
Oh, no.
Harry...
Sick.
- Sick. You're really sick.
- Sick, Miss Teschmacher?
Sick, when I'm mere days from executing
the crime of the century?
No, no, no. Step away from that, please.
How do you choose to congratulate
the greatest criminal mind of our time?
Do you tell me that I'm brilliant?
Oh, no, no.
That would be too obvious, I grant you.
Charismatic. Fiendishly gifted.
Try "twisted."
Get away from there.
Get away, get away, get away!
Tell me something, Lex.
Why do so many people have to die
for the crime of the century?
Why? You ask why?
Why does the phone always ring
when you're in the bathtub?
Why is the most brilliantly
diabolical leader of our time...
...surrounding himself
with total nincompoops?
I'm back, Mr. Luthor.
Yes, I was just talking about you.
You were followed again.
In spite of those catlike reflexes.
Mr. Luthor. Mr. Luthor, I'm sorry.
Otis.
Is that the newspaper
I asked you to get me?
Yeah.
Why am I not reading it?
Because I haven't given it to you yet?
Right.
At last, it's official.
Thanks to the government,
we will pull off...
...the greatest real-estate swindle
of all time.
Lex, what is this obsession
with real estate?
All the time, "land, land, land."
Miss Teschmacher, when I was 6 years old,
my father said to me...
"Get out."
Before that. He said,
"Son, stocks may rise and fall.
Utilities and transportation systems
may collapse.
People are no damn good.
But they will always need land...
...and they'll pay through the nose
to get it."
"Remember," my father said...
- Land.
- Right.
It's a pity that he didn't see
from such humble beginnings...
...how I've created this empire.
An empire? This?
Miss Teschmacher,
how many girls do you know...
...who have a Park Avenue address
like this one?
Park Avenue address?
Two hundred feet below.
Do you realize what people
are shelling out up there...
...for a few miserable rooms
off a common elevator?
- What more could anyone ask?
- Olsen!
- Yeah?
Get this Loch Ness update
right into Composing.
Yeah? No, that's it, Roth.
Put it to bed. Right.
- What are you standing around here for?
- I'm not...
- I wasn't gonna say it.
- Go.
- The sex maniac profile.
- Right.
Look, 9-5 it's a Pulitzer Prize winner.
What do you bet?
There's no Z in "brassiere."
Hey, nice job on that union scandal, Kent.
Well, gosh, thanks, Mr. White.
Oh, hi, Clark. Good night.
- Here, let me carry that for you.
- Oh, thanks a lot.
Lois, have you got a minute?
Excuse me, please. Lois?
And these two go to the addresses
on the envelope, okay?
Lois, I was wondering if you
would like to have dinner with me?
Gosh, Clark, I'm sorry. I'm booked.
Air Force One's landing at the airport
and this kid's there...
...to make sure you-know-who answers
a few questions he'd rather duck.
- My goodness, don't you ever let up?
- What for?
I've seen how the other half lives.
My sister, for instance.
Three kids, two cats, and one mortgage.
I would go bananas in a week.
Oh, can I take you to the airport?
Not unless you can fly.
- Clark? Ladies.
- Sorry.
- Change my clothes. Thank you. Bye.
- Hey, Lois, maybe we could...?
Lois?
- Would you be a pet and mail that for me?
- Oh, sure... Good night.
Going down, please. Going down.
- Going down?
- Going up, up, up.
Good night.
- Daily Planet Copter One, this is ground.
- Planet One, go ahead.
We have Miss Lane here for a quick ride
to Metropolis Airport to meet Air Force One.
Roger, we're on our way
and have you in sight.
Have one aboard for transfer, over.
Roger, Planet One. You're cleared.
Wind, 0-2-0 at 1-5, gusting.
- Altimeter 2-niner-8-niner.
- Roger, over and out.
A malfunction. Can't get liftoff.
- You hooked the tail.
- What's happening?
- Set it down.
- Oh, my God!
We've lost stabilizer rotor control,
I can't hold it!
I can't hold it! I can't hold it!
Wake up!
Help!
Help! Help!
Come on, step back. Step back, folks.
All right, let's get back a little.
Move over across the street.
Bring the cameras over here. Okay.
Okay, you see the helicopter up there?
Help me!
All right, move back.
Let the ambulance through.
There's somebody in there!
Help me!
Okay. Come on, hold it. Get back.
Come on. Come on, get off the streets.
Come on, get back.
Move, let the firemen through.
Boys, come on, now. Make a line.
Move to the other side of the street.
Come on. Get along.
Get away from the building.
Hold these crowds back. Move. Move.
Help me!
- Say, Jim, whoa!
- Excuse me.
That's a bad outfit.
Okay, Bresslaw, move these people out.
Oh, God, look up there.
What the hell's that?
Easy, miss. I've got you.
You... You've got me?
Who's got you?
I can't believe it. I just cannot believe it.
He got her.
Gentlemen, this man needs help.
Well, I certainly hope this little incident
hasn't put you off flying, miss.
Statistically speaking, of course,
it's still the safest way to travel.
Right. Wait.
Who are you?
A friend.
Bye.
You enjoyed it.
I don't know what to say, Father.
I'm afraid I just got carried away.
- I anticipated this, my son.
- You couldn't have.
You couldn't have imagined...
How good it felt?
You are revealed to the world.
Very well. So be it.
But you still must keep
your secret identity.
Why?
The reasons are two.
First: You cannot serve humanity
28 hours a day.
- 24.
- Or 24...
... as it is in Earth time.
Your help would be called for endlessly.
Even for those tasks which human beings
could solve themselves.
Because they're happy to abuse
their resources in such a way.
And secondly?
Second:
Your enemies will discover...
... their only way to hurt you:
By hurting the people you care for.
Thank you, Father.
Lastly:
Do not punish yourself
with your feelings of vanity.
Simply learn to control them.
It is an affliction common to all,
even on Krypton.
Our destruction could have been avoided
but for the vanity of some...
... who consider us indestructible.
Were it not for vanity, why...
... at this very moment...
... I could embrace you in my arms...
... my son.
Reports are coming in of...
- ... a miraculous saving of Air Force One...
- A burglar was apprehended...
- ... by a man in a blue suit and red cape.
- ... rescuing Miss Lois Lane...
... writer on the Daily Planet,
with one hand, and a...
Yeah, that'll be the day, huh?
I said, that'll be the day
when a guy could fly, huh?
Oh, I don't know.
You'd be surprised.
- fantastic hoax.
Your guess is as good as anybody's.
True or false, miracle or fraud?
- The answer to that...
- Miss Teschmacher!
Turn it off.
Lex, what's the story on this guy?
Do you think he's the genuine article?
- If he is, he's not from this world.
- Why?
If any human being were gonna
perpetrate such a fantastic hoax...
...it would have been me.
Otis! My robe!