[ Man Narrating ]
Last week, as you recall...
our space family's lost planet was rocked
by a series of savage earthquakes.
Little did they dream
that in less than 20 desperate hours...
a cataclysmic explosion
would rip apart the planet's core...
and disintegrate
their entire world...
into galactic dust.
Penny, you look like one of those
old-fashioned milkmaids...
coming back from the pasture.
You know, it would be good
to see a pasture again...
walking through the grass,
looking for four-leaf clover...
- wading--
- [ Loud Explosion ]
- [ Ground Shaking, Rumbling ]
- Oh!
Penny.!
In the ship.! Now.!
Penny!
It's slacking off.
Do you think it's as bad
up at the drill site?
I don't think so,
but it could be heading their way.
I'd better warn them.
Don. Come in, Don.
I don't know what's causing this disturbance,
but I do know one thing.
It's happening at a depth that could
crack the core of this planet...
and lay it wide open.
- Don! Come in, Don!
- Right here,John.
Listen, that last batch
of deutronium fuel tested out just fine.
- I think we've finally got all we need.
- Well, that's good news.
How about the earthquake?
Give you any trouble?
- Earthquake? What earthquake?
- Well, we got it here, but good.
And deeper than anything
we've ever had before.
You'd better pack your gear and get back here
right away. The next one may hit your area.
We'll start right back.
Judy, get Will and Smith.
I'll start loading
the equipment.
In the presence of appreciative
colleagues and fellow voyagers...
- I now unveil--
- Will, Dr. Smith. We're leaving.
- Shh!
- Dad just called.
He said there might be an earthquake
right here in this very area.
Am I or am I not going to receive
the reverence this ceremony deserves?
You've got it, Dr. Smith.
As I was saying--
William.
You too.
I now unveil
this noble monument...
a temple of immortality...
to the living
and imperishable memory...
of Dr. Zachary Smith.
I name thee
''Spirit of Space.''
But, Dr. Smith,
it doesn't even look like you.
It is the abstract,
artistic concept of my inner self.
- Now can we leave?
- My dear boy, have you no regard
for the sanctity of this moment?
We've gotta get out of here.
Didn't you hear whatJudy said?
- We might be right in the middle of--
- [ Loud Explosion ]
- [ Ground Shaking, Rumbling ]
- Oh! Oh!
- No, no! Don't fall!
- Hit the dirt!
- You okay?
- Oh! How about you?
Your father was almost right.
He said the next one may hit in this area.
- Where's Smith and Will?
- They were on the other side
of the ridge when it happened.
Come on.
Ah. Not even a crack.
It will endure forever.
Oh.
[ Chuckling ]
Earth folk, from the look of you.
''Snoopingest'' bunch
you ever met.
- What are you after?
- Our drill site's up there.
That's where we get
the fuel for our ship.
And may I add, sir,
that we are not addicted to snooping.
We were much too involved
dedicating my monument.
Were ya?
Hmm.
Beats me why a livin' man
would wanna fool with, uh...
[ Tap Tap ]
dead stone.
On the contrary, my dear sir.
It will outlast us all.
Even that earthquake left it
completely unharmed.
That was no earthquake.
That was me-- blastin'.
I'd have put up a sign if I'd knowed
I was gonna have company.
Name's, uh, Nerim.
What's yours?
- I'm Will Robinson.
- Will.
And I am Dr. Zachary S--
[ Will ]
Have you been here long, Mr. Nerim?
Oh, long enough
to get my bearin's.
- [ Tap Tap ]
- Hey!
- Uh-- I-I didn't mean any harm.
- No offense.
- Where do you come from?
- Oh, hither and yon...
in, uh, in the galaxy
of the Southern Fish.
Home's, uh, catty-corner
from Fomalhaut...
if you know where that is.
- Well, I've heard of it.
- My dear sir...
at the risk
of appearing curious...
may I ask what were you
blasting for?
- Cosmonium.
- ''Cosmonium''?
Cos-- I don't believe
I've ever heard of it.
I don't suppose it's very...
precious?
Oh, it is,
if you know how to get it...
and what to do with it.
Purely out of scientific curiosity,
Mr. Nerim...
I wonder if we might be allowed
to inspect your mining operation.
Oh, naturally,
we will reciprocate...
by letting you
see our drill site.
Well, I reckon
there's no harm.
I got the claim all staked.
[ Whistles ]
- Follow me.
- Yes.
Dr. Smith,
we've gotta get back.
Nonsense, my boy. It's only because
they feared we had an earthquake.
But when we return,
we'll inform them...
that it was just some of Mr. Nerim's
harmless blasting.
Didn't look
so harmless to me.
Don't quibble, Will.
Come along.
And now, sir,
where is your mine entrance?
Oh, down there.
It ain't a bad little ride.
It's been part ''degravitized...''
so just do as I do.
[ Exhales Forcefully ]
I don't see him down there.
Neither do I.
[ Nerim, Voice Echoing ]
Are ya comin'or ain't ya?
Well, we mustn't allow
our fear...
to subdue our scientific curiosity,
must we?
Well, then let's go.
[ Screaming ]
- Oh, good heavens!
- Wow.
What? Oh! I'm frightened.
I don't like this at all.
- Wow.
- What's going on? Heavens!
- [ Whistles ]
- [ Nerim Laughing ]
That wasn't too much
of a drop, was it?
Well, how do we
get back up?
Well, the same way
you got down, sonny.
Just blow a little air out of your lungs
to get you started.
That's all.
Then... kick off.
[ Laughing ]
Hey. Hey, you, uh--
You need heavier boots than you got on
to walk around here.
Here. Uh, I'll, uh--
I'll sweep them out of the way.
But-- But, Mr. Nerim,
they're diamonds.
Dang nuisance is all
they are to me.
No sooner do I sweep
one lot out of the way...
than there's another slew of'em
droppin' down from the ceiling.
[ Chuckles ]
See what I mean?
Now, uh, let's
get over here...
and I'll show you
my refining plant.
Hey. Uh, come on, sonny.
Mr. Nerim, is it possible
that what you refine...
is more precious than diamonds?
[ Chuckling ]
You sure ask a lot of fool questions.
A man don't go prospectin'
a dozen light-years from home...
less'n it's worth his while.
Here. Start shovelin' ore,
Zach boy.
''Zach boy''?
Indeed!
Uh, Will, would you mind?
My back is very delicate today.
Faster.
[ Whistles ]
Be ready to...
draw some off in a minute.
Aren't you going to an awful lot
of trouble just to fill that tiny flask?
Quiet, Will. Good things always
come in small doses.
Mr. Nerim may be in the process of
capturing the very quintessence of,uh--
Just what is cosmonium
the quintessence of, Mr. Nerim?
That there is a mighty
pretty word, Zach boy.
''Quintessence''
is just what this is.
Quiet.
Here it comes.
Ah.
Another two or three of these
and I'll be ready to pull out.
But aren't you going to tell us
what its properties are, Mr. Nerim?
I assure you, sir, whatever you care to reveal
will be held in the strictest confidence.
You have my word of honor
on that.
It looks like you've got
little bits of sun there, Mr. Nerim.
Don't be ridiculous, Will.
What possible use could there be
for ''little bits of sun''?
Oh, the boy's smarter
than you are, Zach boy.
''Bits of sun''
is just about what this is.
Quintessence of the living force...
that thaws the ice
and melts the snow and...
[ Blows Gently ] puts living breath
in everything that grows.
That's a sight more precious
than diamonds, ain't it, Zach boy?
Cosmonium...
the quintessence of the living force.
- It's beyond price.
- Beyond any price you could come up with, mister.
Well, now,you boys
better get on up top.
I got me some more
blastin' to do.
Are you sure that blasting
isn't kinda dangerous?
No. Why, I know the geology of this here
planet like the back of my hand.
A little shakin' here and there
don't do it no harm.
Uh, don't forget to blow out some breath
when you're in the shaft.
Oh, Mr. Nerim.
We shall, of course, meet again.
Can't think of no good reason
why we should.
Perhaps I'll think of a reason.
Naturally, we shall hold
Mr. Nerim's revelations...
in the strictest confidence,
my boy.
- I promised, you know.
- Blow, Dr. Smith.
Ah, yes.
[ Exhales ]
- You gotta kick off.
- Oh, yes. Kick off.
Will! Dr. Smith!
[ Will ]
Over here,Judy.
Didn't you hear us call you?
Where have you been?
Like the camels of the desert, we found shelter
from the storm in a natural harbor.
Now make like a racehorse at the track.
We've gotta get back to the ship.
Racehorse indeed, Major!
No, no! This way,
you blithering bumpkin.
That second quake you got
at the drill site gave us a reading...
twice as intense
as the one we got here.
I don't think this planet
can stand much more.
- Well,John, what will happen to it?
- [ Loud Explosion ]
[ Ground Shaking, Rumbling ]
[ Shouts, Indistinct ]
Hit the circuit breaker!
[ Shouting, Indistinct ]
Is this what Mr. Nerim
calls ''a little shaking''?
It's nothing more than that, my boy.
[ Screaming, Yelling ]
Our fellow voyagers don't seem to have
very good sea legs, do they?
They're not even
good landlubbers.
[ Rumbling Subsides ]
There.
There. It's over.
[ Sighs ] When I think
how much cosmonium...
Mr. Nerim will get after this--
Not that I envy him,
of course.
But what wouldn't I give
to have it.
Begin report
on seismic disturbance.
''Meioseismal'' area
of shock increasing.
Region of seismic focus
now distributed over entire planet.
Subterranean displacement
of geologic structure...
total and continuous.
Core of planet in condition
of molten ferment!
- It's worse than I thought.
- How bad?
I'm afraid we're on a merry-go-round
of chain reaction.
In a matter of hours,
this planet will cease to exist.
It'll disintegrate
into cosmic dust.
''Cosmic dust. ''My dear professor,
cosmic dust indeed.
Dr. Smith,
would you prefer gamma rays?
Ah, well, I don't suppose I'd be
betraying too much of a confidence...
if I told you that all of
these alarums and excursions...
are merely the result of some
completely harmless detonations...
set off by a most remarkable
mining engineer--
my very good friend,
Mr. Nerim.
And just where is this very remarkable
mining engineer, Dr. Smith?
- Oh, he's buried.
- No, Dad. He's really there.
We both saw him. He's got a big excavation
down there up near the drill site.
- And lots of equipment for--
- For his own private smelting process.
- What does he smelt?
- You wouldn't understand,
my dear, any more than I do.
But after all,
this is a free planet.
It's a disintegrating planet,
Dr. Smith.
And regardless of what your
very good friend, Mr. Nerim, told you...
about his detonations
being harmless...
I'm convinced he doesn't know
what he's doing...
and he's made it impossible
for us to remain here any longer.
Well, can't we stop him
from doing any more blasting?
Even if we could, darling,
it wouldn't do any good.
He's begun a destructive process
that can't be stopped.
Come, come, Professor.
Let's not throw everyone into a tizzy.
I can assure you,
on the most reliable authority--
Never mind the reliable authority,
Smith. I agree with John.
This may be a free planet,
but your buddy-- whoever he is--
has made a condemned
world out of it.
- How long do we have?
- Twelve, 1 5 hours at the outside.
That means all systems have to be go
tomorrow morning at 0600...
- especially the fuel system.
- And your destination is where?
Where's it's always been, Smith--
Alpha Centauri.
Indeed. I might have considered
yielding to your panicky pressures...
if your destination
were Earth.
But under the circumstances,
I can only repeat...
that your apprehensions
are ill-founded.
I find this all rather a bore.
I think I'll take a nap.
Stand aside please.
Thank you.
Why, he doesn't understand a thing
you've been telling him.
Now, we'll deal
with him later.
You better take the children and clear out
the light stuff from the camp area.
Don and I will take care
of the heavy equipment.
We're gonna have a weight problem
for takeoff, so--
- So throw out everything we don't need.
- Right.
All right.
Come on, children.
[ Sighs ]
Well, we've got work to do.
John, do you think
we'll be able to make it?
It's really gonna be
touch-and-go.
- [ Loud Explosion ]
- [ Ground Shaking, Rumbling ]
Look out!
Come on now.
Hurry up.
You never realize
how much stuff you accumulate...
until you have
to get rid of it.
Proving that the acquisitive instinct
is still with us.
Come on. Help me fold up this table.
We're gonna need that.
All right.
Mom says I have to get rid
of all this junk.
Well, that's what you're supposed to do
with junk, isn't it?
But it's my own special junk.
I'm very fond of it.
[ Warbling ]
Bloop. Bloop.
Well, maybe if you left the Bloop
behind, you could take some of it.
- Will, how could you?
- I was only kidding.
- [ Loud Explosion ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Ground Shaking, Rumbling ]
- [ Warbling ]
Will.! Penny.!
[ Screaming ]
- Oh! You all right? Oh,John.
- Yes, thank you.
I suppose that was another one of
Dr. Smith's friend's harmless detonations.
No. It was the aftereffect
of all the earlier ones.
I studied those ore samples
from the drill site.
The inner shell of this planet's cracking,
releasing the molten iron core.
- We're gonna have to lift off
sooner than we planned.
- Ready or not.
Oh, we'll be ready.
Let's get back to work.
What is all this,
some sort of midnight revel?
Hammering, thumping, screeching at the top
of your voices-- disturbing my nap.
We happen to have a deadline
for liftoff, Dr. Smith. Remember?
- Oh, that again.
- Come on, girls.
Cosmic dust, molten core
and gamma rays--
all that bogeyman terminology
for scaring children.
How tiresome it all is.
Can't you get it through
that thick skull of yours...
that this planet is cracking up and that
we're getting off it before it does?
Oh, yes, Major, ''cracking up.''
Another bogeyman word.
Well, Godspeed you,
as they say.
Is there anything I can do
to expedite your departure?
Yes. As a matter of fact, you can take
the Chariot, go up to the drill site...
pick all the equipment up that's
lying around and bring it back here.
[ Loud Bang ]
Delighted to oblige. As a matter of fact, I was
thinking of going over there this evening...
to have a little chat
with my friend, Mr. Nerim.
So that, in actual fact, I will be killing
two birds with one stone, so to speak.
May I have the key
to the Chariot?
Thank you, Major.
Never fear.
Smith is here.
? Oh, my darling
Oh, my darling ?
? Oh, my dear cosmonium ??
[ Gasps ]
- [ Braying ]
- Oh, Robur, what's eatin' you?
[ Sighs ] We got us a heap
of trouble, Robur.
You ain't been gnawin'
on this here thruster control, have ya?
Oh, real trouble
is what we got, Robur.
Blasted too much rock
for my own good.
This here planet
is fallin' apart...
and here we are without no way
to get off of it 'fore it does.
[ Chariot Approaching ]
Uh-oh. Looks like
we got company.
[ Chariot Stops ]
Oh. Him again.
Mr. Nerim.
Mr. Nerim,
my great old friend.
I saw your lamp
in the window from afar...
and I knew your latchstring
would be out for me.
What are you after now?
But-- But, my dear sir,
you misjudge me.
Possibly you don't realize it, but I
have been your most loyal defender.
You can't defend
what ain't been attacked.
But you have been attacked, sir,
from all sides.
My fellow travelers-- or should I say
my ex-fellow travelers--
are convinced that,
because of your blasting, this planet...
in a matter of hours,
will disintegrate into cosmic dust.
[ Scoffs ]
Now, isn't that ridiculous?
- Uh--
- It-- It is ridiculous, isn't it?
Well, it's the stupidest
fool nonsense I ever heard.
This here planet has got
layers and layers of rock...
so solid you could lay
a burnin' sun right on it...
and the sun would just
burn itself out...
and leave the planet
untouched.
That's exactly what I told them,
but they wouldn't listen.
They're leaving
for Alpha Centauri.
Of course, they'll never make it.
As a matter of fact...
I seriously doubt whether their ship
is capable of leaving the ground.
Do you always get this happy when
other folks is in trouble, Zach boy?
But Mr. Nerim,
I feel for them. I do.
But they're really
not my kind.
There's not one among them
I could call ''partner...''
partner.
Are you, uh,
aimin' to be, uh...
my partner?
Nothing would
please me more.
Prospecting is in my blood, you see.
My great-great-grandfather
was a forty-niner...
and my Uncle Thaddeus discovered
the Comstock Lode all by himself.
Of course, they were
only after mere gold...
not anything as priceless
as cosmonium.
They never would have
understood its worth as we do.
Eh, partner?
I've got to be honest
with ya, Zachy.
I been a loner
most of my life...
and I'm gettin'
too old to change now.
Uh, this little poke
of cosmonium...
is about the last
of the diggin's for me.
It's gonna be like my pension fund,
if I ever get back home.
But it don't look like
I ever will now.
- Why not?
- [ Sighs ]
Busted thruster control
on my spaceship.
[ Sighs ]
I'd give anything for a spare...
even gamble
with my pension fund.
You would?
You would gamble
with this priceless substance?
Most of it, I reckon,
if I had to.
Oh, but what's the use?
No one's gonna bet with me.
Well, uh,
be of good cheer, my friend.
The sky's always darkest
just before the dawn.
- Huh?
- Every cloud has a silver lining.
- It-- It does?
- Yes.
And it's an ill wind
that blows nobody any good.
I may return.
- [ Door Closes ]
- [ Engine Starts ]
Oh.
[ Sighs ]
How much more time
do we have, Mother?
About three hours at the most,
according to your father.
Ah! How doth the little busy bee
improve each shining hour.
Dr. Smith, we are not bees.
And there is nothing very shining
about 3:00 in the morning.
We just all happen to have a very
sensible instinct for self-preservation.
''Sensible,'' madam? I don't wish
to sound discouraging, dear lady...
but the chances of the Jupiter 2
being able to budge from this spot...
are roughly
a thousand-to-one against.
I can assure you,
without fear of contradiction...
that this planet, like
the Jupiter itself, is here to stay.
- [ Loud Explosion ]
- [ Ground Shaking, Rumbling ]
Roll 'em, partner.
Roll the dice.
The quintessence
of the living force.
Take one drop at bedtime...
and live forever.
Oh, Dr. Smith, do you still think
this planet is here to stay?
Indubitably, madam.
[ Sighs ]
''Madam.''
- Will, can you get me the soldering kit, please?
- Sure, Dad.
Why not face it, gentlemen?
I'm afraid that all the king's horses
and all the king's men...
will never put Jupiter
together again.
- You wanna bet?
- I'd be stealing your money, Major.
If you haven't anything
more constructive to contribute...
get outside
and unload the Chariot.
That's really what I came in
to talk to you about, Professor.
My mission was a failure.
I lost my way.
- You lost your way?
You've been up there a hundred times.
- But never in the dark.
- Here, Dad.
- Thank you.
It means losing a couple hours
of my working here if I go up now.
- Maybe we'd better forget it.
- No. Some of that equipment may be vital to us...
if and when we land
on Alpha Centauri.
Maybe I should go with him, Dad.
I've been up there at night.
All right, Dr. Smith,
you can go back up there with Will.
But regardless ofhow you feel about
such bogey words as ''cosmic dust... ''
I want you both back here
within two hours at the outside.
Your wish is my command, sir.
We're almost there, Dr. Smith.
I thought you said you didn't
know your way in the dark.
Did I? Well, perhaps my eyes have grown
accustomed to the darkness by now.
- There's the turnoff.
- Later, my boy. Later.
I have a little something
to deliver to Mr. Nerim.
The poor man
needs a spare part for his ship.
You can't give him that!
That's a thruster control!
- Where'd you get it?
- No cause for alarm, my dear boy.
- I found it on the junk pile.
- Oh.
Ah. Here we are.
- [ Both Laughing ]
- There.
- Yes.
- I don't see why you have to play cards...
with Mr. Nerim, Dr. Smith.
- Why don't you just give him--
- Mr. Nerim is a proud and conscientious man.
His pride would not allow him
to accept charity.
That's right, son.
Never accepted no charity
in my whole life.
I'd rather gamble
with my life savings than do that.
He means his cosmonium.
What a brave man he is.
- And you'd take it.
- Only if I won it.
There's many a slip
twixt the cup and the lip.
Now, sir, shall we cut for deal?
A 1 0 of galaxies.
And all I've got...
is a deuce of asteroids.
Looks like you're
startin'out lucky, Zach boy.
Galaxies? Asteroids?
I don't believe
I understand these cards.
Well, there's nothin'
to understand.
Uh, galaxies is, uh,
the big ones.
Then planets.
Uh, then satellites.
All the way down to asteroids.
[ Ground Shakes, Rumbles ]
Hey, Dr. Smith,
I think we better get out of here.
Nothing to worry about.
Just a little, uh, resettling.
That's all. Uh, loser deals.
Right, Zach boy?
Uh, yes, of course.
[ Chuckling ]
What you got, Zach boy?
Well, well.
Galaxies. A pair.
I believe you said
they were the highest.
Mighty good...
and always a winner.
Except...
when somebody else
has got a supernova.
Supernova?
You mean I lost?
Well, you can't win 'em all,
Zachy boy.
It's all right, Dr. Smith.
You said you wanted to lose.
- Remember?
- Of course. How can I forget?
Aren't you going
to give me a chance for revenge?
Well, I don't need nothin' but this.
Besides, I-I gotta
get outta here.
I ain't got no time. It looks like your
friends was right about this planet.
It ain't gonna be nothin'
but cosmic dust pretty quick.
What? It can't be.
You told me--
Well, I guess my calculations
went a mite haywire.
- Now look here, Mr. Nerim!
- [ Nerim Exhales Forcefully ]
Mr. Nerim?
Mr. Nerim!
- You come right back here!
- That's the way the planet crumbles.!
- [ Laughing ]
- The base perfidy of the man.
Oh, the pain.
The pain.
Never mind about that, Dr. Smith.
Didn't you hear what he said?
- We've gotta get out of here.
- My dream shattered.
The quintessence
of the living force gone forever.
Look! He left these two flasks.
We'd better return 'em to him.
No hurry, my boy.
No hurry.
Well, it wasn't a total loss
after all, was it?
I'm not sure what you mean
by that, Dr. Smith...
but if we don't get outta here,
it's us who are gonna be a total loss.
Oh, no, no.
We can't let that happen...
now that this priceless treasure
has been bestowed upon me.
[ Ground Shaking, Rumbling ]
Well, don't just stand there!
We must hurry!
[ Exhaling Forcefully ]
- Dr. Smith!
- Oh.
Ah-choo!
[ Indistinct Yelling ]
Oh, goodness.!
Oh! Oh! Oh, dear!
[ Whimpering ]
Come on!
Oh, dear! Oh!
- [ Rumbling Subsides ]
- [ Sighs ]
- There. That's better.
- [ Loud Blast ]
There he goes!
And without his cosmonium.
You don't sound too unhappy
about that, Dr. Smith.
Let's get back
to the drill site.
Will. Will!
My monument!
No!
Oh, dear!
It was so proud
and imperishable.
- We'd better go, Dr. Smith.
- Will.
Help me to set it right.
What's the use?
It can't last anyway.
Despite your misgivings,
my monument will endure forever--
in one position or another.
[ Straining ]
Oh!
[ Grunts ]
Push, Will!
[ Straining ]
My cosmonium!
Will! Help me!
[ Straining, Grunting ]
Will, help me to scoop it up.
Dr. Smith, we're leaving at 0600...
and that's less than
three hours from now.
And we still gotta get
the drilling equipment.
Yes. Yes.
Adieu.
Come, Will.
[ Roars ]
[ Growling ]
- [ Exhales ]
- Is this really necessary, my boy?
Major West himself said
he was perfectly willing...
to forget all of this
drilling equipment.
Dad said we may need it
on Alpha Centauri.
Then why did we have
to leave the Chariot so far away?
Dad said
we had to conserve fuel.
Oh, the pain.
The pain.
Alpha Centauri, of all places,
when Earth is so close.
He'll never make it. I really
must have a serious talk with him.
- He won't listen to you.
- Why not?
You've made
too many mistakes lately.
First you said the blasting
was harmless...
and then you said the planet
would never break up.
Indeed. Must a man be haunted
by a few trivial errors in his past?
- [ Shrieks ]
- [ Growling ]
- [ Dr. Smith Whimpering ]
- It's alive!
- I think it wants something.
- [ Footsteps ]
- Give him the tool chest!
[ Growling ]
- [ Dr. Smith Shrieks ]
- Let's get back to the Chariot!
[ Shrieks ]
Keep trying to raise them by radio.
I'll do the same.
- Roger.
- I'll keep in touch with you as well.
- All right. Stand clear.
- Bye, Dad.
- Bye.
-John.
You've got to find them,
even if it means--
Yes. Even if it means
delaying our liftoff.
- Don't worry.
- All right.
[ Engine Blasts ]
Will.
I'm over the weather station area.
Come in if you see me.
Will. Report your position.
- [ Shrieking ] Run! Run! Run!
- [ Growling ]
He'll crush us.
Up, Will! Help me up!
- I think he wants your cosmonium.
- My cosmonium? Never.
Never!
[ Screeching ]
- It won't start!
- You have to turn on the ignition.
- What?
- Turn on the ignition!
Oh, dear!
I can't move!
[ Growling ]
Get away!
[ Shrieking ]
Dr. Smith, you'll have to
give it to him now!
Give him your pocketknife.
Maybe that will satisfy him.
Dr. Smith, he doesn't
want my pocketknife!
- He wants the cosmonium!
- Huh?
That's what must have
brought him to life.
- [ Growling ]
- [ Shrieking ]
There!
[ Growling ]
I guess it wasn't
enough for him.
Please!
Please go away!
- [ Creature Growling ]
- [ Dr. Smith Shrieking ]
[ Laser Firing ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Growling ]
Help me up, Will. Oh!
Oh! Oh!
Thank you, Professor. Thank you.
Will, I should never have listened
to you and given him my cosmonium.
I'm sure I could have
persuaded him to leave without it...
in another moment or two.
- Here. Give me a hand.
- Dr. Smith, in another moment or two...
you wouldn't have been around
to do anything.
Neither will any of us if we don't get
back to that ship in a hurry. Let's go!
- Are we ready?
- Ready as we'll ever be.
All right.
Liftoff s in five minutes.
[ Ground Shaking, Rumbling ]
Well, I wasn't
entirely sure until now.
I don't need
any more proof after this.
I'll make one last check below.
We're nearly ready, dear.
Where's Smith? Smith!
Never fear.
Smith is here.
- What have you got there?
- My motion sickness remedy.
- All right. Take it and get in the chair.
- Cheers.
Oh. I don't suppose
there's anything more I could say...
that would make you change your mind
about our destination?
We're not gonna go through
all that again now, are we, Doctor?
You realize, of course, that no
human eye has ever seen Alpha Centauri.
- All buckled up?
- We can't even be sure that it's habitable.
- I'm well aware of that, Doctor.
- In that case...
I strongly urge that we change our course
for a place that we know really exists.
Get in that chair, Smith,
and buckle your seat belt.
- All secure?
- Robot in magnetic lock.
I will maintain myself in magnetic lock
until further orders.
Ah, that's a thrilling
bit of news...
you bumbling birdbrain.
- Well, the children are all ready.
- Fine.
Now, we'll go into orbit
at minimum apogee...
and remain in orbit
around this planet until--
well, until
there is no planet.
After that, we'll be free
of gravitational pull and on our way.
Couch belts will remain fastened till
I give the order that they be removed.
- Understood?
- Yes.
We may not be able to communicate
with each other for a little while, Penny...
so is there anything
you'd like to ask me?
- Is Debbie gonna be all right?
- [ Warbling ]
- Oh, she'll be just fine.
- Dad, are you sure you're not gonna need me...
to help out on top?
Well, it's gonna be
a tough job, but, uh...
Don and I will do
the best we can.
And don't worry about Dr. Smith.
I'll take care of him.
What a comfort you are
in my hour of need.
Judy.
You look simply beautiful.
[ Chuckles ]
Thank you, Dad.
- I--
- What?
- [ Kiss ]
- What's that for?
Well, because
I'm so proud of you...
and because you've taken
such good care of us.
And because...
I love you.
Oh, yes. There's something
I forgot to tell you.
You've been
the most uncomplaining...
patient partner a man could wish for
while we've been here.
Thank you, darling.
Well, there's been
a very good reason for it.
You.
- You just have time to strap up.
- All right.
Five seconds.
Three, two--
- [ Warbling ]
- one.
- Zero!
- Firing one and two!
[ Yelps ]
I suppose, at any moment now, the planet
will disintegrate into cosmic dust...
if the professor's predictions
are accurate.
Disintegrate indeed. Bah!
[ Loud Explosions ]
- Three-second burst on five.
- Roger.
- [ Beeping ]
- No power.
We're starting to roll! We can't
pull free of the planet's gravity!
We're getting a heat feedback.
The thrusters can't take hold.
- Try a five-second burst on the main bank again.
- Roger. Here goes.
We're losing control!
- [ Beep ]
-John?
John,
what's happening to us?
We can't pull free.
We have a short in our thruster control.
- Hang on. We'll fix it.
- Oh.
I sure wish we had
that old thruster control now.
- What do you mean?
- There was one on thejunk pile.
Dr. Smith gave it to
that old mining engineer.
If only I hadn't done it.
It's all up with us now because of me.
I didn't find it
on the junk pile.
I found it
on the central Astro-lever.
Well, I think you better get right
up there and tell them what you did.
I can't do it now.
I'm strapped in.
- Well, then unstrap and get right up there.
- If you insist.
- Will, I think you'd better go up with him.
- Yes, ma'am.
You, uh-- You will bear me out,
won't you, Will...
when I tell them
that I meant no harm?
It was just--
It was just a vagrant impulse.
You'll have to
explain that yourself.
I don't know what
''a vagrant impulse'' means.
[ Explosions Continue ]
What are you doing up here?
You had strict orders.
Dr. Smith has something
to tell you, Don.
- What is it?
- [ Dr. Smith ] Nothing at all.
That is, if you're able to repair
what appears to be wrong.
- So far, no luck.
- You'd better tell him, Doctor.
- I only did it out of the goodness of my heart.
- Did what?
Donated one of our thruster controls
to Mr. Nerim.
- The one that was there.
- Why, I ought to--
- [ Loud Explosion ]
- [ Yelps ]
Hold on!
The planet's blowing!
We're losing pressure!
- Oh!
- Try number five now!
It's working!
- Maureen.
- Yes?
You can relax now.
I think we're finally
on our way.
Oh. Good.
So out of the goodness of your heart,
you nearly signed all our death warrants.
Except his own, naturally.
He was quite sure that all the king's
horses and all the king's men...
couldn't put the Jupiter
back together again.
Believe me, Major. I have the deepest
admiration for your remarkable ingenuity.
Nothing pleases me more
than to be proved wrong.
You sure know how to
change your mind fast, Dr. Smith.
When circumstances
demand it, my boy.
Well, I take it that Dr. Smith
explained what he did.
Well, darling, Dr. Smith's explanations
are like a box of magic tricks.
Mom! Dad!
Come here. Quick.
- It's a nova flare.
- Oh, look.
[ Maureen ]
Look. It's like a rainbow after a storm.
After the storms we've been through,
I think we're entitled to it.
Oh!
I think I see
a familiar planet out there.
That's not a planet, Dr. Smith.
That's a red dwarf star.
- For a moment, I thought it might be--
- Forget about it, Smith.
Whatever you thought it might be,
we happen to be pulling away from it...
at about 50 percent
of light velocity.
Light velocity.
Oh, dear.
I can feel my motion sickness
coming back.
Oh, the pain.
The pain.
We must be nearly a million miles
out in space, Dad.
- Closer to two million, son.
- Wow. We must be traveling at
close the speed of light.
-Just about, Will.
- What a pity we have no idea
where we're traveling to.
We'll know once we spot a familiar star
and get a fix on it.
The trouble is there are billions
of stars out there...
and they all look familiar.
He's right. I can't tell
one from the other.
Of course not, silly.
You don't know anything about astronomy.
But Dad does,
and so does Don.
That is devoutly
to be wished.
Howsoever, I think I shall
do a little stargazing on my own.
You mean you're gonna take
another nap.
Spare me the barbs, Major.Just remember,
they laughed at Copernicus too.
You, sir, come with me.
And you can
come with me, my dears.
I wanna stay here with Dad and Don.
They may need my help.
- Not as much as I do.
- Holy cow.
Now, let's see.
Earth should be back here.
[ Alarm Beeping ]
-John!
- Maneuver around it!
[ Switches Flipping ]
We can't get around it!
We've had it!
Oh! Oh!
[ Shrieking ]
We're gonna crash!